<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Adnan Shaikh</title>
    <description>Adnan Shaikh's personal website and blog.</description>          
    <link>adnanshaikh.com</link>
    <atom:link href="adnanshaikh.com/feed.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
      <item>
        <title>Improving Network Latency</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;My friends and I recently got into a new tactical shooter called
&lt;a href=&quot;https://playvalorant.com/en-us/&quot;&gt;Valorant&lt;/a&gt;. It’s a great game but the only
thing holding us back from having an enjoyable experience was our latencies
since we live on opposite sides of the planet. To mediate our latencies, we
usually settle for a middle ground and that always happens to be European
servers and although my average ping hovered around 140 ms, it wasn’t very
consistent. Random ping spikes would ruin clutch moments. It bothered me enough
to finally route a LAN cable around my house and see what sort of a difference
it would make and wow did it make a difference. You can find some of the
differences in latencies and speeds for 2.4 GHz, 5 GHz, and LAN below. Your
mileage may definitely vary with regards to switching to a wired solution since
factors like crowded frequency spectrums, range, and periodic network scanning
determine how bad your WiFi experience can be.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Wed, 30 Sep 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
        <link>adnanshaikh.com/2020/09/30/improving-network-latency/</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">adnanshaikh.com/2020/09/30/improving-network-latency/</guid>
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Offline-first workflows</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;A common problem I face while working on my computer or any device for that
matter is frequent context switching. Part of the problem can be blamed on the
allure of the novelty of what the internet has to offer. Googling for something
as simple as centering a &lt;code class=&quot;language-plaintext highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;&amp;lt;div&amp;gt;&lt;/code&gt; element has me opening at least 5+ tabs, but
this behavior isn’t just limited to programming solutions. If I’m casually
scrolling on Reddit, I’m bound to open a tab for every link I find interesting
and get sucked into a rabbit hole. Even as I write this post, my mind keeps
wanting to procrastinate and work on low-effort tasks like fixing the file
watcher for the &lt;code class=&quot;language-plaintext highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;jekyll serve&lt;/code&gt; that’s broken on WSL2 on Windows. What’s to blame
for the advent of this distracted behavior? The tools or the user? I think it’s
a combination of both. While I’m known to exercise self-control in other aspects
of my life, it’s mentally draining to have to prune out choices and stick to a
task at hand. Are there better ways of using tools to meet our needs?&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Thu, 12 Mar 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
        <link>adnanshaikh.com/2020/03/12/offline-first-workflows/</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">adnanshaikh.com/2020/03/12/offline-first-workflows/</guid>
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Falling In Love With The Process</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;Delaying gratification is hard and it’s as if the goals that I embark upon as I
get older seem to push this feeling further and further away. Over the past few
years, I’ve experimented with different techniques to get myself to work,
whether that be structuring my environment to prime habits more easily, setting
up negative reinforcement methods like Beeminder or just through practicing
mindful awareness by journaling. What I’ve found is that while I haven’t had
any long-lasting success with any of these methods, I’ve already mastered one
form of getting uncomfortable work done, going to the gym.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Sat, 18 Jan 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
        <link>adnanshaikh.com/2020/01/18/falling-in-love-with-the-process/</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">adnanshaikh.com/2020/01/18/falling-in-love-with-the-process/</guid>
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Writing an Xposed Module to Quit Social Media</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;Over the last year, I’ve been mindfully evaluating my usage of different
services and actively pruning out those that offered more noise over signal. I
started the year off by muting everybody on Facebook and Instagram. This got rid
of the endless feed for me and dramatically reduced the time I spent on the app
and improved my overall mood. What was left of my feed was just a string of
greyed out stories and photos from my own feed populating the main page.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Wed, 25 Dec 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
        <link>adnanshaikh.com/2019/12/25/writing-an-xposed-module-to-quit-social-media/</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">adnanshaikh.com/2019/12/25/writing-an-xposed-module-to-quit-social-media/</guid>
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>A Hacky GPU Switcher</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;With the arrival of my Razer Core X eGPU enclosure, I was pretty excited to get
back into some video editing and gaming, but there was a massive issue. My video
and audio streams were both stuttering as soon as I’d plug it in. A bit of
googling led to me to the solution to disable my integrated GPU from the Device
Manager. That was odd though, I didn’t see any complaints from users with
dedicated NVIDIA GPUs in their machines. I figure NVIDIA Optimus must have
something to do with this. Anyway, with a working solution I could finally begin
automating this procedure.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Sat, 30 Nov 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
        <link>adnanshaikh.com/2019/11/30/a-hacky-gpu-switcher/</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">adnanshaikh.com/2019/11/30/a-hacky-gpu-switcher/</guid>
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>What I'm doing now - November 2019</title>
        <description>&lt;h1 id=&quot;what-im-doing-now---november-2019&quot;&gt;What I’m doing now - November 2019&lt;/h1&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Mon, 11 Nov 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
        <link>adnanshaikh.com/2019/11/11/now-november/</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">adnanshaikh.com/2019/11/11/now-november/</guid>
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Free as in free time</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;4 months ago, I decided to abstain from using social media and overall it’s been going really well. I have to admit though I haven’t been completely off for good. I keep slipping back in everytime I’m bored but I’m glad I decided to mute everyone when I did quit. The only thing I do now is go through everyone’s greyed out stories which aren’t really interesting. Once I got comfortable living without social media, it got me thinking about other omnipresent services I use in my life. Namely, Google.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Thu, 18 Apr 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
        <link>adnanshaikh.com/2019/04/18/free-as-in-free-time/</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">adnanshaikh.com/2019/04/18/free-as-in-free-time/</guid>
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Wallpaper Algorithm</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;I’m currently reading The New Turing Omnibus and one of the first exercises mentioned in Chapter 1 was implementing the Wallpaper algorithm with 3 colors. Although the premise of the chapter was to simply get acquainted with the conventions of how algorithms would be written in the book, they picked a pretty mesmerizing one. Here’s the algorithm, straight from the book.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Sun, 27 Jan 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
        <link>adnanshaikh.com/2019/01/27/algorithmic-wallpaper/</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">adnanshaikh.com/2019/01/27/algorithmic-wallpaper/</guid>
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>What I'm doing now - January 2019</title>
        <description>&lt;h1 id=&quot;what-im-doing-now---january-2019&quot;&gt;What I’m doing now - January 2019&lt;/h1&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Wed, 09 Jan 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
        <link>adnanshaikh.com/2019/01/09/now-january/</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">adnanshaikh.com/2019/01/09/now-january/</guid>
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Nutrition Basics - Macromolecules</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;Organic cells are composed of molecules that based on 4 fundamental elements:
&lt;strong&gt;Carbon&lt;/strong&gt;, &lt;strong&gt;Hydrogen&lt;/strong&gt;, &lt;strong&gt;Nitrogen&lt;/strong&gt; &amp;amp; &lt;strong&gt;Oxygen&lt;/strong&gt; (and more!) Combining these
elements, you can create 4 major macromolecules &lt;strong&gt;Carbohydrates&lt;/strong&gt;, &lt;strong&gt;Lipids&lt;/strong&gt; &amp;amp;
&lt;strong&gt;Proteins&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Wed, 01 Aug 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
        <link>adnanshaikh.com/2018/08/01/nutrition-macros/</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">adnanshaikh.com/2018/08/01/nutrition-macros/</guid>
      </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
